The world's first Street Art disaster movie...
Exit Through the Gift Shop is a documentary film directed by Banksy.
Banksy is a graffiti artist with a global reputation whose work can be seen on walls from
post-hurricane New Orleans to the separation barrier on the Palestinian West Bank.
Fiercely guarding his anonymity to avoid prosecution, Banksy has so
far resisted all attempts to be captured on film.
Exit Through the Gift Shop tells the incredible true story of how an eccentric French shop keeper turned documentary
maker attempted to locate and befriend Banksy, only to have the artist turn the camera back on its owner.
Narrator, played by Rhys Ifans.
Self, played by Thierry Guetta.
Self, played by Banksy.
Self, played by Shepard Fairey.
Self, played by INVADER.
Self, played by Debora Guetta.
Exit Through the Gift Shop is a 2010 British documentary
film directed by street artist Banksy.
It tells the story of Thierry Guetta, a French immigrant in Los Angeles who, over several years, filmed a host of
street artists at work, including Shepard Fairey and Banksy, but failed to do anything with the footage.
Eventually, Banksy decided to use the footage to make a documentary, which
includes new footage depicting Guetta's rise to fame as the artist "Mr.
Brainwash".
In addition to narration read by Rhys Ifans, the story is largely related by Banksy
himself, whose face is obscured and voice altered to preserve his anonymity.
Geoff Barrow composed the film's score, and Richard Hawley's "Tonight The
Streets Are Ours" plays during the opening and closing credits.
The film premiered at the 2010 Sundance Film Festival on 24 January 2010, and was
nominated for Best Documentary Feature at the 83rd Academy Awards.
Since its release, there has been extensive debate over whether the
film is a genuine documentary or a mockumentary.
When asked if the film was real, Banksy simply replied, "Yes."
The film explores themes of painting, graffiti, fraud, cousin, street artist.